Wonder by RJ palaso be kind to Nature AN ANNOUNCEMENT CAME over the huge speakers next to the
stadium lights: “Welcome, everyone. Welcome to the 23rd annual Big Movie Night at
the BR word Nature Reserve. Welcome, teachers and students from MS 342: the
William Heath School. A big cheer went up on the left side of the field. “Welcome,
teachers and students from Glover Academy. Another cheer went up, this time
from the right side of the field. “And welcome, teachers and students from the
Beacher Prep School!” Our whole group cheered as loudly as we could. “We’re
thrilled to have you as our guests here tonight, and thrilled that the weather
was cooperating— —in fact, can you believe what a beautiful night this is?” Again,
everyone whooped and hollered. “So as we prepare the movie, we do ask that you
take a few moments to listen to this important announcement. The Brood Nature
Reserve, as you know, is dedicated to preserving our natural resources and the
environment. We ask that you leave no litter behind. Clean up after yourselves.
Be kind to nature and it will be kind to
you. We ask that you keep that in mind as you walk around the grounds. Do not
venture beyond the orange cones at the edges of the fairground Do not go into
the cornfields or the woods. Please keep the free roaming to a minimum. Even if
you don’t feel like watching the movie, your fellow students may feel otherwise,
so please be courteous: no talking, no playing music, no running around. The
restrooms are located on the other side of the concession stands. After the movie
is over, it will be quite dark, so we ask that all of you stay with your schools
as you make your way back to your buses.
Teachers, there’s usually at least one lost party on Big Movie Nights at
brawood don’t let it happen to you!
Tonight’s movie presentation will be The Sound of Music I immed imately started
clapping, even though I’d seen it a few times before, because it was Via’s
favorite movie of all time. But I was surprised that a whole bunch of kids (not
from beer booed and hissed and laughed.
Someone from the bottom right of the field even threw a soda can at the
screen, which seemed to surprise Mr.
Tushman. I saw him stand up and look in the direction of the can thrower, though
I knew he couldn’t see anything in the dark. The movie started playing right
away. The the stadium lights dimmed. Maria the nun was standing at the top of the
mountain twirling around and around. It had gotten chilly all of a sudden, so I
put on my yellow monok hoodie and adjusted the volume on my hearing aids
and leaned against my backpack and started watching. The hills are
[Music]
alive the woods are alive SOMEWHERE AROUND THE boring part where the guy
named rol and the oldest daughter are singing You are 16 going on S 17 Jack
nudged me. “Dude, I’ve got to pee,” he said.
We both got up and kind of hopscotched over the kids who were sitting or laying
down on the sleeping bags. Summer waved as we passed and I waved back. There were
lots of kids from the other schools walking around by the food trucks,
playing the carnival games, or just hanging out. Of course, there was a huge
line for the toilets. “Forget this, I’ll just find a treat said Jack.
“That’s gross, Jack. Let’s just wait,” I answered. But he headed off to the row of
trees at the edge of the field, which was past the orange cones that we were
specifically told not to go past. And of course I followed him. And of course we
didn’t have our flashlights because we forgot to bring them. It was so dark now
we literally couldn’t see 10 steps ahead of us as we walked toward the woods.
Luckily, the movie gave off some light, so when we saw a flashlight coming toward
us out of the woods, we knew immediately that it was Henry, Miles, and Amos. I guess
they hadn’t wanted to wait online to choose the toilets, either. Miles and
Henry were still not talking to Jack, but Amos had let go of the war a while ago.
And he nodded hello to us as they passed by. “Be careful of the bears!” shouted Henry,
and he and Miles laughed as they walked away. Amos shook his head at us like,
Don’t pay attention to them. Jack and I walked a little farther until we were
just inside the woods. Then Jack hunted around for the perfect tree and finally
did his business, though it felt like he was taking forever. The woods were loud
with strange sounds and chirps and croaks, like a wall of noise coming out
of the trees. Then we started hearing loud snaps not far from us, almost like
cap gun pops, that definitely weren’t insect noises. And far away, like in
another world, we could hear Raindrops on roses and whiskers on
kittens “Ah, that’s much better,” said Jack, zipping up. “Now I have to pee,” I said,
which I did on the nearest tree. No way I was going farther in like Jack did. “Do
you smell that? Like firecrackers,” he said, coming over to me. “Oh yeah, that’s what
that is,” I answered, zipping up. “Weird.” “Let’s go
alien WE HEADED BACK the way we came, in the direction of the giant screen. That’s
when we walked straight into a group of kids we didn’t know they' just come out
of the woods, doing stuff I’m sure they didn’t want their teachers to know about.
I could smell the smoke now, the smell of both firecrackers and cigarettes. They
pointed a flashlight at us. There were six of them: four boys and two girls. They
looked like they were in the seventh grade. “What school are you from?” one of
the boys called out feed your Prep!” Jack started to answer, when all of a sudden
one of the girls started screaming. “Oh my God!” she shrieked, holding her hand over
her eyes like she was crying. I figured maybe a huge bug had just flown into her
face or something. “No way!” one of the boys cried out, and he started flicking his hand in
the air like he just touched something hot. And then he covered his mouth.
“No freaking way, man! No freaking way!” All of them started half laughing and half
covering their eyes now, pushing each other and cursing loudly. “What is that?”
said the kid who was pointing the flashlight at us, and it was only then
that I realized that the flashlight was pointing right at my face, and what they
were talking about— —screaming about— —was me. “Let’s get out of here,” Jack said to me
quietly, and he pulled me by my sweatshirt sleeve and started walking
away from them. “Wait wait wait!” yelled the guy with the flashlight, cutting us off.
He pointed the flashlight right in my face again, and now he was only about 5
feet away. “Oh man! Oh man!!” he said, shaking his head, his mouth wide open. “What
happened to your face?” “Stop it, Eddie,” said one of the girls. “I didn’t know we were
watching Lord of the Rings tonight!” he said. “Look, guys, it’s Gollum!” This made his friends
hysterical. Again we tried to walk away from them, and again the kid named Eddie
cut us off. He was at least a head taller than Jack, who was about a head taller
than me, so the guy looked huge to me. “No
man, it’s Alien said one of the other
their kids. “No, no, no, man. It’s an orc!” laughed Eddie, pointing the flashlight in
my face again. This time he was right in front of us. “Leave him alone, okay?” said
Jack, pushing the hand holding the flashlight away. “Make me,” answered Eddie,
pointing the flashlight in Jack’s face now. “What’s your problem, dude?” said Jack.
“Your boyfriend’s my problem!” “Jack, let’s just go,” I said, pulling him by the arm. “Oh
man, it talks!” screamed Eddie, shining the flashlight in my face again. Then one of
the other guys threw a firecracker at our feet. Jack tried to push past Eddie,
but Eddie shoved his hands into Jack’s shoulders and pushed him hard, which made
Jack fall backward. “Eddie!” screamed one of the girls. “Look,” I said, stepping in front of
Jack and holding my hands up in the air like a traffic cop where a lot smaller
than you guys “Are you talking to me Freddy Krueger? I don’t think you want to
mess with me, you ugly freak,” said Eddie.
And this was the point where I knew I should run away as fast as I could, but
Jack was still on the ground and I wasn’t about to leave him. “Yo, dude,” said a
new voice behind us. “What’s up, man?” Eddie spun around and pointed his flashlight
toward the voice. For a second, I couldn’t believe who it was.
“Leave him alone, dude,” said Amos, with Miles and Henry right behind him. “Says
who?” said one of the guys with Eddie. “Just leave him alone, dude,” Amos replied calmly.
“Are you a freak, too?” said Eddie. “They’re all a bunch of freaks!” said one of his
friends. Amos didn’t answer them but looked at us. “Come on, guys, let’s go. Mr.
Tushman’s waiting for us.” I knew that was
a lie, but I helped Jack get up, and we started walking over to Amos. Then out of
the blue, the Eddie guy grabbed my hood as I passed by him, yanking it really
hard so I was pulled backward and fell
flat on my back. It was a hard fall, and I
hurt my elbow pretty bad on a rock. I couldn’t really see what happened
afterward, except that Amos rammed into the Eddy guy like a monster truck and
they both fell down to the ground next to me. Everything got really crazy after
that. Someone pulled me up by my sleeve and yelled, “Run!” and someone else screamed,
“Get him at the same time, and for a few seconds I actually had two people
pulling the sleeves of my sweatshirt in opposite directions. I heard them both
cursing, until my sweatshirt ripped and the first guy yanked me by my arm and
started pulling me behind him as we ran, which I did as fast as I could. I could
hear footsteps just behind us, chasing us, and voices shouting and girls screaming,
but it was so dark I didn’t know whose voices they were, only that everything
felt like we were underwater. We were running like crazy, and it was pitch
black, and whenever I started to slow down, the guy pulling me by my arm would
yell, “Don’t stop voices in the dark FINALLY, AFTER WHAT seemed like a forever of running,
someone yelled: “I think we lost them!” “Amos?” “I’m right here!” said Amos’s voice a few
feet behind us. “We can't stop!” Miles yelled from farther up. “Jack!” I yelled.
“Whoa!” said Jack. “I’m here.” “I can’t see a
thing!” “Are you sure we lost them?” Henry asked, letting go of my arm. That’s when I
realized that he’d been the one who was pulling me as we ran. “Yeah.” “Shh! Let’s
listen!” We all got super quiet, listening for footsteps in the dark. All we could
hear were the crickets and frogs and our own crazy busy panting. We were out of
breath, stomachs hurting body spent over our knees. “We lost them,” said Henry. “Whoa! That
was intense!” “What happened to the flashlight?” “I dropped it!” “How did you guys
know?” said Jack. “We saw them before.” “They look like jerks.” “You just rammed into
them I said to Amos. “I know, right?” laughed Amos. “He didn’t even see it coming!” said
Miles. “He was like, ‘Are you a freak, too?’ and you were like, bam! said Jack. “Bam!” said
Amos, throwing a fake punch in the air.
“But after I tackled him, I was like, run, Amos, you smuck he’s 10 times bigger than
you! And I got up and started running as fast as I could!” We all started laughing.
“I grabbed doggy and I was like, ‘Run!’” said Henry. “I didn’t even know it was you
pulling me!” I answered. “That was wild,” said Amos, shaking his head. “Totally wild.” “Your
lip is bleeding, dude.” “I got in a couple of good punches,” answered Amos, wiping his
lip. “I think they were seventh graders.” “They were huge.”
“Losers!” Henry shouted really loudly, but we all shushed him. We listened for a
second to make sure no one had heard him. “Where the heck are we?” asked Amos. “I
can’t even even see the screen.” “I think we’re in the cornfields,”
answered Henry. “Duh, we’re in the cornfields,” said Miles, pushing a corn stock at
Henry. “Okay, I know exactly where we are,” said Amos. “We have to go back in this
direction. That’ll take us to the other side of the
field.” “Yo, dudes,” said Jack, hand high in the air. “That was really cool of you guys
to come back for us. Really cool. Thanks.” “No no problem,” answered Amos, high-fiving
Jack. And then Miles and Henry high-fived him, too. “Yeah, dudes, thanks,” I said, holding my
palm up like Jack just had, though I wasn’t sure if they’d high five me, too
amus looked at me and nodded. “It was cool how you stood your ground, little dude,” he
said, high-fiving me. “Yeah Augie said Miles, high-fiving me
You were like, ‘We’re little than you guys’
“I didn’t know what else to say!” I laughed.
“Very cool,” said Henry, and he high-fived me, too. “Sorry I ripped your sweatshirt.” I
looked down, and my sweatshirt was completely torn down the middle. One
sleeve was ripped off, and the other was so stretched out it was hanging down to my
knees. “Hey, your elbows bleeding,” said Jack.
“Yeah.” I shrugged. It was starting to hurt a lot. “You okay?” said Jack, seeing my face.
I nodded. Suddenly I felt like crying, and I was trying really hard not to do
that. “Wait, your hearing aids are gone!” said Jack. “What!” I yelled, touching my ears.
The hearing Ed band was definitely gone.
That’s why I felt like I was underwater!
“Oh no!” I said, and that’s when I couldn’t hold it in anymore. Everything that had
just happened kind of hit me and I couldn’t help it: I started to cry. Like
big crying, what Mom would call “the waterworks.” I was so embarrassed I hid my
face in my arm, but I couldn’t stop the tears from
coming. The guys were really nice to me, though. They patted me on the back. “You’re
okay, dude. It’s okay,” they said. “You’re one brave little dude, you know that?” said
Amos, putting his arm around my shoulders.
And when I kept on crying, he put both his arms around me like my dad would
have done and let me cry the emperor's guard WE BACKTRACKED
THROUGH the grass for a good 10 minutes to see if we could find my hearing aids,
but it was way too dark to see anything.
We literally had to hold on to each other’s shirts and walk in single file
so we wouldn’t trip over one another. It was like black ink had been poured all
around. “This is hopeless,” said Henry. “They could be
anywhere.” “Maybe we could come back with a flashlight,” answered Amos. “No, it’s okay,” I
said. “Let’s just go back. Thanks, though.” We walked back toward the cornfields, and
then cut through them until the back of the giant screen came into view. Since it
was facing away from us, we didn’t get any light from the screen at all until
we’d walked around to the edge of the woods again. That’s where we finally
started seeing a little light. There was no sign of the seventh graders anywhere
or Where do you think they went?” said Jack. “Back to the food truck said Amos.
“They’re probably thinking we’re going to report them.” “Are we?” asked Henry. They
looked at me. I shook my head. “Okay,” said Amos, “but, little dude, don’t walk around
here alone again, okay? If you need to go somewhere, tell us and we’ll go with you.”
“Okay.” I nodded. As we got closer to the screen, I
could hear High on a hill was aone only goed and could smell the cotton candy
from one of the concession stands near the food trucks. There were lots of kids
milling around in this area, so I pulled what was left of my hoodie over my head
and kept my face down, hands and pockets, as we made our way through the crowd. It
had been a long time since I’d been without my hearing aids, and it felt like
I was miles under the earth. It felt like that song Miranda used to sing to me:
Ground Control to Major Tom, your circuit’s dead, there’s something
wrong I did notice as I walked that Amos had stayed right next to me. And Jack was
close on the other side of me. And Miles
was in front of us and Henry was in back of us. They were surrounding me as we
walk through the crowd of kids. Like I had my own emperor’s
guard sleep Then they came out of the narrow valley and at once she saw the
reason. There stood Peter and Edmund all the rest of alon's army fighting
desperately against the crowd of horrible creatures whom she had seen
last night; only now, in the daylight, they looked even stranger and more evil and more
deformed I STOPPED THERE I’d been reading for over an hour and sleep still
didn’t come. It was almost 2: a...m..
Everyone else was asleep. I had my flashl on under the sleeping bag, and maybe the
light was why I couldn’t sleep, but I was
too afraid to turn it off. I was afraid of how dark it was outside the sleeping
bag. When we got back to our section in front of the movie screen, no one had
even noticed we’d been gone. Mr. Tushman and Miss Ruben and Summer and all the
rest of the kids were just watching the movie. They had no clue how something bad
had almost happened to me and Jack. It’s so weird how that can be, how you could
have a night that’s the worst in your life, but to everybody else it’s just an
ordinary night night Like all my calendar at home, I would mark this as
being one of the most horrific days of my life. This and the day Daisy died. But
for the rest of the world, this was just an ordinary day. Or maybe it was even a
good day. Maybe somebody won the lottery today. Amos, Miles, and Henry brought me
and Jack over to where we’d been sitting before, with Summer and Maya and Reed and
then we went and sat where they had been sitting before, with seina and Savannah
and their group. In a way, everything was exactly as we had left it before we went
looking for the toilets. The sky was the same. The movie was the same. Everyone’s
faces were the same. Mine was the same.
But something was different. Something had changed. I could see Amos and Miles
and Henry telling their group what had just happened. I knew they were talking
about it because they kept looking over at me while they were talking. Even
though the movie was still playing, people were whispering about it in the
dark. News like that spreads fast. It was what everyone was talking about on the
bus ride back to the cabins. All the girls, even girls I didn’t know very well,
were asking me if I was okay. The boys were all talking about getting revenge
on the group of seventh grade jerks, trying to figure out what school they
were from. I wasn’t planning on telling the teachers about any of what had
happened, but they found out anyway.
Maybe it was the torn sweatshirt and the bloody elbow. Or maybe it’s just that
teachers hear everything. When we got back to the camp, Mr. Tushman took me to
the first AE office, and while I was getting my elbow cleaned and bandaged up
by the camp nurse, Mr. Tushman and the camp director were in the next room
talking with Amos and Jack and Henry and Miles, trying to get a description of the
troublemakers. When he asked me about them a little later, I said I couldn’t
remember their faces at all, which was wasn’t true. It’s their faces I kept
seeing every time I closed my eyes to sleep. The look of total horror on the
girl’s face when she first saw me. The way the kid with the flashlight, Eddie,
looked at me as he talked to me, like he
hated me. Like a lamb to the slaughter. I remember Dad saying that ages ago, but
tonight I think I finally got what it meant thanks for watching please
remember to like and subscribe it really helps the channel see you in the next video
[Music]